<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>powershell on tig&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.blog.tiga.tech/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in powershell on tig&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:09:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.blog.tiga.tech/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VeeamNotify -  Veeam B&amp;R session notifications</title>
      <link>https://www.blog.tiga.tech/posts/veeamnotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:09:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blog.tiga.tech/posts/veeamnotify/</guid>
      <description>VeeamNotify sends Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication session summary notifications to Discord, Microsoft Teams, and Slack, detailing the session result, various statistics, and optionally alerting you via @mention when a job finishes in a warning or failed state.
VeeamNotify is a replacement for my previous VeeamDiscordNotifications project, and the respective Teams and Slack projects. You may have seen my previous blog post about VeeamDiscordNotifications.
VeeamNotify features improvements across the board and support for all the aforementioned messaging services in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Deploy Telegraf and Windows Monitoring Configurations with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.blog.tiga.tech/posts/install-telegraf-posh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 02:33:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blog.tiga.tech/posts/install-telegraf-posh/</guid>
      <description>I recently made this script to deploy the Telegraf metrics agent to Windows systems.
This is primarily designed for Windows Server but can also be pushed to workstations.
Overview Requirements Setup Usage Example Screenshots Commands Parameters Overview This is a Telegraf deployment script for Windows Server* environments.
By default, the script will install a base configuration which includes:
Telegraf agent as system service (configurable). Your pre-configured output plugin. A comprehensive system metrics input plugin configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
